THOMAS GLASER

58 Forest Road, Windsor, SL4 4HU

07480 503 505 - thomas@tkglaser.net

PROFILE

I have 16 years commercial experience as a Software Engineer, Team Lead and Architect. During that time I have received consistently excellent feedback about my technical expertise, my pro-active approach and my clear and honest communication. I am especially passionate about clean code and applying tried and proven architectural patterns to solve real world problems.

Key skills: Cloud Architecture, Full Stack Development using Microsoft technologies, Angular and NodeJS.

SKILLS	
Web Frameworks and Technologies	
TypeScript (JavaScript)	5 Years
Angular	5 Years
HTML+CSS	10 Years
ASP MVC, Razor	3.5 Years
Backend Frameworks and Technologies	
C# / .Net / .NET Core	12 Years
MS SQL Server with Entity Framework	3 Years
NodeJS	1 Year
Leadership	
Technical Team Lead	4 Years
Architect	3 Years
CONTINUING EDUCATION	



Microsoft Certified: Azure Solutions Architect Expert

I always strive to extend my knowledge and keep up to date with current trends. I do this using various sources like podcasts, books and PluralSight courses. Recent topics include:

- **Architectural Patterns** for High availability, Cloud Architecture in **MS Azure**, **Kubernetes**, **Helm**, Identity Management, **Kafka** and Hadoop to name just a few.
- I am a Microsoft Certified Azure Solutions Architect Expert (Certification Number: H394-0016)

EXPERIENCE

MCLAREN APPLIED - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

April 2019 - March 2020

Co-architected and co-developed multiple Angular+NodeJS+.NET Core applications.

Frameworks/Languages: **Angular** (v9), **NodeJS**, **.NET Core**, **SignalR**, **RxJS** (Reactive extensions for JS), **NgRx** (State manager), **NestJS** (API Framework for Node), **Angular Schematics**, **TypeScript**, **C**#

- I created a Template Web Application to Kick-Start customer projects. This consisted of a NodeJS backend handling security and administration and a frontend in Angular. This included CLI tooling to tailor the application to the project's needs. The CLI was written in NodeJS using Angular Schematics.
- Implemented 3D telemetry visualisation using ThreeJS and D3. The telemetry data was received from a .NET Core backend using SignalR. I've also worked on an Authentication layer in NodeJS against Auth0 using OpenID Connect.
- Co-architected a new authentication layer for the Telemetry Analytics Platform (.NET Core)
- Worked on the CICD build pipelines (Azure DevOps)

MAGNITUDE INTERNET GMBH - CHIEF ARCHITECT, CO-FOUNDER

Oct 2014 - Jul 2019

Designed and co-developed an E-Commerce Solution.

Frameworks/Languages: Ms Azure Cloud, C#, ASP.NET MVC 5, ASP Web API 2, AngularJS

- I came in as the Chief Architect for this German Start-up company.
- Designed the cloud based architecture (MS Azure) for their multi-tiered product and mentored the team on the concepts used.
- Worked together with the CTO on implementing the CICD pipeline in Atlassian Bamboo. (It was a pain, I'd use Azure DevOps going forward)

INVENIAS - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

October 2018 - March 2019

Re-implementation of Web-Based CMS in Angular 7.

Frameworks/Languages: **Angular** (v7), **RxJS** (Reactive extensions for JS), **NgRx** (State manager), **C#**, **Visual Studio 2017**, **Visual Studio Code**.

This client was struggling with performance issues, maintainability and stability. I've taken the following steps to move them forward:

• Start to re-implement the application using several new concepts in a side-by-side way, so the improvements can be seen immediately. Many new features were implemented along the way.

- Introduce NgRx for client-side state management and caching.
- Migrate from Angular 4 to Angular 7 to take advantage of out-of-the-box performance improvements.
- Move them to the new Angular CLI build system. This took dev builds from 8 minutes down to 2.
- Set up code linting to highlight anti-patterns and use of deprecated features.
- Mentor the team on all the new concepts so that they can to move forward.

FISERV - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

October 2017 – October 2018

Re-implementation of Risk Assessment Software in Angular 5.

Frameworks/Languages: C#, WebAPI, Angular (v5), RxJS (Reactive extensions for JS), NgRx (State manager), Visual Studio 2015, Visual Studio Code, MS SQL Server.

The old version of the FCRM risk assessment software was implemented in Silverlight and had to be reimplemented in Angular. This included writing a REST API wrapper for the legacy server-side logic using WebAPI. The client-side application was then created from scratch using Angular.

I did some work on the server-side back-end, but I mainly focused on the client-side Angular application and ended up writing about 80% of the app on my own. There was a heavy focus on observability (data changes in one part of the UI affecting other parts), so we heavily used the NgRx, @ngrx/entities and @ngrx/effects packages to manage and observe client-side state changes.

KNIGHT FRANK - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2015 – September 2017

Extending and updating Knight Frank's web presence.

Frameworks/Languages: C#, ASP MVC, .NET Core 1.1, AngularJS (1.x) Angular (2.x), jQuery, ASP WebApi, WebForms, Visual Studio 2015, MS SQL Server

I have rewritten Knight Frank's property search application from scratch. I have also done multiple smaller projects for Knight Frank, including:

- A UK stamp duty calculator (JavaScript/jQuery) http://www.knightfrank.co.uk/stamp-duty-calculator
- A new office and people search plugin (AngularJS, WebAPI)

COUCHBASE INC. - SOFTWARE TRAINER (CONTRACT)

July 2015 - Oct 2016

I have trained some of Couchbase's customers in the use of the Couchbase C SDK (libcouchbase).

HM INFORMATIK AG - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

Mar 2014 – June 2015

I have written multiple plugins for a Flight Control Simulation software (FCS). Frameworks/Languages: C++, Boost, CMake, QT 4.8, Visual Studio 2010, Bazaar.

MOMENTUM COACH HIRE LTD - IT DIRECTOR, SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CONSULTANT

Sep 2011 - Mar 2014

I have been working for Momentum Coach Hire, a small ambitious company in the Coach Hire and Event Organisation business. There, I have created a variety of new web sites and improved existing ones. I've moved some of the existing ones to Azure, all the new ones were hosted on Azure from the start. I have also been promoted to IT Director and was responsible for the migration of the entire company (50 employees) onto Microsoft Office 365.

Frameworks/Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC 3-4, Google Maps API, MS Azure

SYMANTEC UK LTD - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb 2010 - Sep 2011

I have worked as a Senior Software Engineer for Symantec UK Ltd in the Research and Development team for Symantec Enterprise Vault, an email archiving solution written in C# and C++.

INGRES EUROPE LTD - SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar 2004 - Feb 2010

With Ingres I worked as a permanently employed Consultant. I was involved in various customer projects as a developer and architect.

EDUCATION

TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF ILMENAU

- Diplom Informatiker (Dipl. Inf.) Equivalent to 2:1 Master in Computer Science
- Primary Subject: Computer Science "Good" (2.2)
- Secondary Subject: Mathematics "Good" (1.7)
- Diploma Thesis: "Toolbox with Interactors for Geometric Modelling in Virtual Reality" "Good" (2.3)
- Various extracurricular Activities like Manager of a Student Club.

INTERESTS

- Open Source Community, Linux
- Racquet Sports

REFERENCES

Excellent references available on request.